[
  {
    "question": "The open science movement is NOT attempting to make science…",
    "choice1": "Commercially appealing",
    "choice2": "Transparent and reproducible",
    "choice3": "Freely available",
    "choice4": "Collaborative and inclusive",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following does NOT belong under the umbrella of open science?",
    "choice1": "Science blogs",
    "choice2": "Open-source software and hardware",
    "choice3": "Educational resources behind paywalls",
    "choice4": "Citizen science",
    "answer": 3
  },
{
    "question": "Which of these benefits does open access bring?",
    "choice1": "Application of your findings by practitioners and policy makers",
    "choice2": "Researchers in developing countries have access to your work",
    "choice3": "Your research gets more exposure and increases chance of getting future funding",
    "choice4": "Easy increase of your scientist impact factor",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these claims about open data is NOT true?",
    "choice1": "Data can be accessed and shared.",
    "choice2": "Data that can be accessed and reused by anyone for any purpose without technical or legal restrictions.",
  "choice3": "Data can be reused free of charge.",
    "choice4": "Data can be sold to other interested parties.",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What is NOT a common condition found in data licences?",
    "choice1": "Attribution",
    "choice2": "Royalties",
    "choice3": "Non-commercial",
    "choice4": "Copyleft or share alike",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the main benefits of documenting your code?",
    "choice1": "Clarity and reproducibility",
    "choice2": "Others can utilise and extend your code",
    "choice3": "To get credited if others use your code",
    "choice4": "Influence on the performance of your code",
    "answer": 4
  },
{
    "question": "Which of the claims about an embargo period on data access is NOT correct?",
    "choice1": "An embargo period is often stated in your consortium agreement, funders’ contract, patent, etc.",
    "choice2": "An embargo period is usually created as a result of unfavourable political or economic circumstances between nations.",
    "choice3": "An embargo period is temporary and at the end of it data will become available by either open or mediated access.",
    "choice4": "An embargo period allows for IP registration (patent, design, copyright).",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be included in a data management plan (DMP)?",
    "choice1": "Data publishing impact",
    "choice2": "Dissemination methods",
  "choice3": "Legal and ethical requirements",
    "choice4": "Data storage and preservation strategy",
    "answer": 1
  },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a FAIR principle?",
    "choice1": "Findable",
    "choice2": "Accessible",
    "choice3": "Identifiable",
    "choice4": "Reusable",
    "answer": 3
  },
{
    "question": "Which type of metadata is NOT the relevant to the FAIR principles:",
    "choice1": "Descriptive metadata",
    "choice2": "Indicative metadata",
    "choice3": "Administrative metadata",
    "choice4": "Structural metadata",
    "answer": 2
  },
 {
    "question": "What is NOT the function of data repositories?",
    "choice1": "To collect data",
    "choice2": "To manage data",
    "choice3": "To archive data",
    "choice4": "To validate data",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Which services provide data centres additional to those of data repositories?",
    "choice1": "Legal advice",
    "choice2": "Unlimited data storage",
    "choice3": "Platforms, tools, processes and specifications",
    "choice4": "Career consultancy",
    "answer": 3
  },
   {
    "question": "Which of the following factors are addressed by open science policies?",
    "choice1": "Restriction and anonymisation of personal data",
    "choice2": "Property rights, copyright and licencing",
    "choice3": "Provision of funding opportunities",
    "choice4": "Open-access publications and publishing standards",
    "answer": 3
  },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following belongs to general principles of scientific integrity?",
    "choice1": "Impertinence",
    "choice2": "Accountability",
    "choice3": "Professional courtesy and fairness",
    "choice4": "Honesty",
    "answer": 1
  },
   {
    "question": "What is your study plan referred to after a journal reviews it?",
    "choice1": "Pre-registration ",
    "choice2": "Registered report ",
    "choice3": "Gold access journal paper",
    "choice4": "Green access journal paper ",
    "answer": 2
  },
{
    "question": "What is a pre-print?",
    "choice1": "A copy of the research hypotheses you have for your research ",
    "choice2": "An infographic which sums up your research ",
    "choice3": "A full draft of a paper sent for peer-review",
    "choice4": "Research protocol",
    "answer": 3
  }
]